<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wireless hippie</title>
    <description>an online diary for a wireless hippie</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 15:28:08 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 15:28:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The first Mars settlers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of the times I start to write something for this blog I write “this is one of the best experiences of my life”, this time I’m going to write about the best experience of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the last three months of my life living in the middle of a toxic wasteland in the Bombay Beach desert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/nothing.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This place feels like the edge of the world, I wonder if the settlers of the far west felt the same way I do in here: a colonizer of an anarchist impossible dead land that exists in the faint equilibrium between the everything and the nothingness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kinds of people you will find in southern west California are on the edge of society, they’re marginals, artists, unstable, stoics, loving, saints […]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This place might as well be &lt;a href=&quot;https://mars.college&quot;&gt;Mars&lt;/a&gt;. A high-tech, low-life cyberpunk fantasy lost in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we might as well be settlers -afterall- colonizing this piece of land with our dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There I heard shady stories about suicides, I was death threatened, I went to the church on Sundays and watched a man meet god and be reborn after life times of suffering. We created and shared together a philosopher’s stone that was an inexhaustible source of creativity, we danced in storms, we built a whole world and we tore it apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/people.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this weird land, that looked both like a western and a Mad-Max movie scenario, filled with fortuneless criminals and wealthy Hollywood artists, I’ve watched myself play many roles. I was an extra, passively watching the world unveiling around me, mesmerized with people’s magnetism, intelligence, sexuality, kindness and madness. I’ve also watched myself play the main role making long lasting impressions in their lives. I taught and learned lessons. I felt so full and so empty, so important, so irrelevant. I had all this time to feel and I’m so grateful. (Grateful every time the train passes by).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/me.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve felt the cold and the beauty of waking up at 5am in the desert to pee by the sound of howling coyotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning I prayed for the sun to come up and was grateful for its warmth. Every morning for a long time.
I’d sit in one of our scavenged chairs from the local dumpster, in the top of the Huaqiangbei, and absorb the sun’s energy and light into my body. Another day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every night, I’d brush my teeth star gazing, wondering about &lt;a href=&quot;https://wireless-hippie.github.io/tenerife-sunset/&quot;&gt;life and death, sociology, and philosophy&lt;/a&gt;. Relishing every second, trying to keep myself in the moment and to hold in me this whole universe so I could never feel alone again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/sky.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared my very few very precious spiritual practices with strangers that later on I came to love. Some of them were gone. I know some will be gone. That hurts. But a friend once taught me how everyone that touches you live for ever through you, and that gives me peace. In the desert I also internalized the Buddhist notion that loss is a facet of pain and an inevitable part of life, however suffering is a choice within you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/party.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve recuperated my long lost loves for &lt;a href=&quot;cyborgdream.github.io/&quot;&gt;so many things&lt;/a&gt;.
I was healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was suddenly so cool to like what I liked and have long discussions about all of these things.
I was accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was so fulfilling and easy to focus and to not see the passing of time.
I had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/mars.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met a few of the most incredible people I ever met in my life. I learned so much about the restorative power of communities and now I can’t see my life without it. Everything looks so much clearer after I waited for the ripples to dissipate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mars/share.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left my castle. I saw an old man, a sick man and a dying man.
And now I can’t go back to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures in this blog post were taken by many Martians!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/martian/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/martian/</guid>
        
        <category>burn</category>
        
        <category>community</category>
        
        
        <category>us</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A fiery virgin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello hippies,
 I’ve just lived an incredible experience I’d like to share with you. This is mainly about how I felt about it, it’s about love, openness and acceptance. Maybe it inspires you to seek for something similar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, some updates about corona: I’m fully vaccinated. Science is a wonderful thing! I’m back in Germany and the numbers here are very manageable, which allows us to live a close to normal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy. Of course I’m happy. But to start life again, talking to people for hours, meeting them in parks, sitting straight on a picnic cloth, and sharing food, do we hug or not,  why is this still a question, can I share my cigarette? Well, I’m healthy but there are still other diseases around right, oh man, my back hurts, my couch is much better, why did I come etc. etc. etc. I just wanted to write it here, that was a couple of tough months and only now I’m being able to turn off this mindset a bit and come back to some “normality”, you’re not alone finding this is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, now to the easy things: I’ve been to my first burner gathering this past weekend. What is a burner? You might have heard of Burning Man, the huge festival happening in whatever desert in the US, maybe even about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goingnowhere.org/core-principles/&quot;&gt;10 principles&lt;/a&gt; that rules the event, but the kind I’m talking about is very different. It was a small event, less than 200 people, we camped in Germany countryside for 4 days and it felt like a parallel universe of pure love and kindness where everyone was doing their best to make everyone around them happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This festival wasn’t about getting high on amphetamines and alcohol and passing out while 180bpm music is literally blasting your tent out. I think that’s why people insist in not calling it a festival. This was about connecting with the inner you of people. I did this before, but I had no idea something in this scale was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fte/fte4.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;  display: block;   margin-left: auto;   margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“[The Japanese people] are so crafty in their hearts that nobody can understand them. Whence it is said that they have three hearts: a false one in their mouths for all the world to see, another within their breasts only for their friends, and the third in the depths of their hearts, reserved for themselves alone and never manifested to anybody.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;From História da Igreja do Japão vol I pg 173, written by Father João Rodrigues, SJ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like as if people were living their third hidden heart openly, sharing it with whoever wanted to see it and take part on it. And that was exactly what I was looking for. After so many months of seclusion and loneliness - connecting to people - be them my friends, strangers, anyone, everyone, is what I strived for the most (even though it’s hard! It’s a bit of a contradictory feeling with this one that I talked about earlier. At the same time I want to open up and embrace the world, I want to curl up and lay on my balcony’s floor. But these feelings, they’re all here and are all valid, I’m just choosing wich one to follow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tell you one of the most brilliant things about this community I’d like to go on a little digression about myself: these past months, I happened to develop a really deep relationship with tattoos. I’ve been tattoing some friends and experimenting on myself, it’s a very meaningful experience to me and I intend to talk about it here once I’m able to do a tattoo trip! A couple of weeks ago I just got a new one done. It’s Haku from Spirited Away, to me it represents how important it is to accept help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fte/tattoo.png&quot; style=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a very strict person and to me is always hard to accept help from others, be them friends, family, strangers, anyone! I feel good helping others, but when asking for help I feel like I’m being cumbersome and needy. I know this is not healthy and I’ve been battling for months to change this tought process and even though I made some progress, it was still very far from a healthy mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this burner showed me how rewarding it is to accept help, to open up and be fragile. By accepting help you’re not “being cumbersome” you’re bringing happiness to people who like to help. You are, perhaps, showing and recognizing your fragilities, talking about them, working on them, which allows you to become a better person. You’re also also connecting with people that are helping you, because they see these fragilities and they see themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experience showed me again how we’re all just humans, struggling with such similar things and striving for such similar things and being content with such similar things. There was people from all around the world in this festival, but it didn’t really matter where you came from, we’d connect the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fte/fte3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved to see people’s third heart and to show mine. I’m thankful for all the beautiful souls that shared this event with me and made it so whimsical. Every and each one of them had their part. These hippies made a deep impression on me and now that I know that this is possible I’ll try to replicate it more often on the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many leafy and dusty hugs. 🍃🔥&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to see you all again and again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/burning-virgin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/burning-virgin/</guid>
        
        <category>burn</category>
        
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To walk into other's dreams</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I always loved stories, and that’s probably the reason why I invested so much time developing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/rpgirlslife&quot;&gt;Role Playing Game group for girls&lt;/a&gt; back in my city instead of studying Electromagnetism for my Electrical Engineering’s degree. I love to tell stories, hear stories, be part of stories. And a dream is a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/rpgirls.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;  display: block;   margin-left: auto;   margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dream as in something oniric is a fabulous story where you can do anything, there are absolutely no boundaries, it’s a fantastic odyssey and usually other people can’t just walk in to these. A dream as in a wish is also a story, a story to be told, a hope, a prayer, an aspiration. It’s much more restricted and often times — contrary to the tales your brain’s garbage-collector is generating for you — reduced, with physical and emotional constraints. But the good thing about these is that if you’re honest and introspective enough, sometimes you can let people into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I walked into someone else’s dream. It was a curious mix between the oniric and the wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m living in this house which is part of a huge complex of a finca in Tenerife. A couple owns this place. When I arrived in the afternoon I was gifted three things: eggs from their own little chicken family that they have around here, one of their apartments in the beach in case the cold weather of their finca was bothering me too much and an unwarned trip into Maria’s dream for three hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/eggs.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;  display: block;   margin-left: auto;   margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maria is an artist and this is me trying to remember and summarize what she said about how her creative process works: “Sometimes I see things, and I know that there’s a story to be told about them. And sometimes I don’t know which story is it, so I study, I read and I research until I understand this story. Once I did I can transfer my dreams into reality.” This is not only the most amazing form of learning, in my opinion, but also an incredible way of creating artifacts of your deeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/outside_dragon.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always understood the importance of seeing the results of your actions towards building dreams. The importance of being grateful and caring about your little achievements. I even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deviantart.com/marimeireles&quot;&gt;tattoed something on myself&lt;/a&gt; this weekend to try to keep it more present in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/tatu.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; style=&quot;  display: block;   margin-left: auto;   margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes it’s really hard to keep track of the path you went through. Either because these achievements are really small or really spaced or sometimes really hard to see because of their abstract nature. Walking into Maria’s dreams I could see beautiful works of art entangled with fascinating stories that were physical tokens of her dreams. I walked amidst, I saw, I heard, I felt, her hopes, her prayers, her interests, her dragons, her kids, her loves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/first_room.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was an immense inspiration to meet her, and I’m incredibly grateful for her to have shared her dreams with me. I hope I can create tokens as real as hers from my achievements and be able to touch people’s souls the way she touched mine, and be able to mix the oniric and the real at least a bit as well as she did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/second_room.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: I can’t condense the experience I had in more details with my broken English. I can’t honour it so I won’t. It’s Maria’s dreams and I was just a guest for a couple of hours. I hope you can come and experience it yourself one day too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.P.S: Here are some bonus photos of the nature surroundings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/outside.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/to-walk-in-anothers-dream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/to-walk-in-anothers-dream/</guid>
        
        
        <category>spain</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A personal digression on sunsets: an illustrated book with Teneriffa's sunsets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was a teenager and lived in my home town in Brazil, I’d watch the sunset every day. It was one of the few opportunities I had to be in touch with nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a farm and until I was 5 I spent the majority of my time surrounded by what felt like endless forests, gardens and fields, filled with more animals and insects and things that I’d never assimilate completely because of its abundance and complexity. I think this magnificent immersion in my formative years shaped me into being a deep nature’s lover for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 10, my grandfather sold this farm. This was a very abrupt cut in my relationship with nature and this sudden change to live a fulltime city life got into me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The memories I had and this urge to go back to nature would sting me quite frequently, leaving a sour taste in my mouth for having moved to the cement jungle. I called myself an anarchoprimitivist and thought most technology was bad and that the human kind did wrong when moved itself away from God’s beautiful creations (I was some kind of religious kid back then). I’d hate on the city, the industry I’d see from my balcony, the car noises, the houses, the capitalists who were financing all of this - in summary I’d hate on a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was this one thing that thrilled my imagination, made my heart beat faster and took a deep sigh out of my chest every time I past through it by the kitchen’s window: a huge forest surrounding an abandoned steel factory nearby. I think one day after rewatching the Lord of the Rings trilogy I finally took the courage to go there. So, I talked my best friend into it, and we waited for the right time in the class breaks to jump over the school’s wall “Into an adventure!”. The long story short is that we got robbed our sweet mp3 players by a crazy crack head with a knife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life. In a very dangerous country, I suppose. This was my first experience that put me in touch with the wickedness of the world. Before that I lived in a childhood’s utopia where everybody is nice to everybody else, after all, why would someone be evil? This question and the questions it implies and implicates really got into me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d spend hours writing endless rants about the meaning of life, physics and philosophy in my old school notebooks while contemplating sunset. Lots of the time these three things would merge together and I’d get myself wondering: what the fuck. I actually miss that a lot. I wanted to be a physicist for the longest time because of these exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/1sunset.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I went watching the sunset by myself in a nearby beach. Didn’t have any notebooks and no one recently robbed my mp3 player from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still, watching sunsets is an interesting exercise to me. It’s a moment where even though I have my phone and the whole world’s knowledge, and all of my friendships, and lots of my desires, expectations, fears, loves, inside this little black magic box, I don’t really feel the urge to look at it and let it consume me. I sit still, and I look at the clouds and at the beautiful colors the sun is creating with the help of our atmosphere and optic enchantments and I just feel gratitude for living in a world filled with beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/2sunset.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also arises interesting sociological questions. All of the times I have gone there, I’m the only female looking person that’s alone and I’m one of the few persons who is alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder why aren’t more females alone in the beach to watch the sunset? In Brazil the obvious answer would be: because it’s dangerous of course - but in Europe, I really wonder. Are women less lonely? They’re usually more often surrounded by friends and family? Do they suffer more pressure to be accompanied always? Are women more social beings on average? Or is there actually a degree of concern that their privacy or body or space won’t be respected because they’re females - even though we’re in Europe? I was personally abused by a guy when eating out by myself in a restaurant just in front this beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I like to be alone watching the sunset because it makes me feel alone. I don’t feel like I spend enough time with myself but being there makes me feel like I can finally breath and think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/3sunset.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch sunsets today but I don’t wonder anymore about the meaning of life, physics or philosophy. It’s funny to me, how it seems like I became a much more enclosed egocentric person looking so much at the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope it’s not a reflex of me becoming insensitive to the rest of the world’s problems because I moved into a place that doesn’t have such glaring problems like Brazil. I hope I’m doing this because my personal life is complicated now, more than it used to be. Maybe the answers I found for these elementary questions are now good enough to ease my soul, and now I feel more comfortable in focusing on improving myself and looking at the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, I can’t wait to have the peace of mind and that itchy feeling of curiosity to spend sunsets thinking about the meaning of life, physics and philosophy again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tenerife-sunset/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tenerife-sunset/</guid>
        
        
        <category>spain</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyprus aerial view</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For my first stop in this end of the world trip I chose Cyprus because of low incidence of corona + was supposed to meet with a friend there, but unfortunately didn’t work. Fortunately I still had another friend with me who accompanied my throughout Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus is a beautiful island in the mediterranean. In recent history it was occupied by Greeks, then by the Ottoman empire then by the British. It has a mix of all of these cultures and it’ll be difficult to find someone that doesn’t speak English in the Greek side. “Greek side” because the island is divided in half between the Greek and the Turkish with an UN buffer zone in the middle to avoid conflicts between both parts. But don’t worry, no imminent war starting, as long as the rest population is as chill about each other as the Cyprus subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus is the first desert-like place I’ve been to. I liked it at first, the desert landscapes awaken some interesting desolating feelings in my birdy soul, but I have to admit that after 2 weeks living in the desert, I was craving for some greenies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/desert.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first nest, near Larnaka. Had some great sunset views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/first-nest.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my stay in there I visited some nice places in the east. There are some beautiful beaches in the east coast with white sand and transparent mesmerizing blue waters. I recommend it strongly if you’re interested in beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you’re around check the Capo Greco park. You can make some sight seeing in there + diving if it’s your thing. I unfortunately am still on a mission of improving my swimming skills. Since I almost died in the Aare River in Bern - Switzerland, I decided to be more respectful to water and more careful around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/capo.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus has a local pine tree, the Mastika, which produces a resine wich they use to make various products. It tastes like eating a tree somewhat, interesting flavor, recommend it.
They also have amazing flat bread with honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of food, I also went to this amazing restaurant in Larnaka, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Maqam+Al-Sultan+Restaurant/@34.9110143,33.6288479,15z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1svegetarian+food+larnaka!3m4!1s0x14e082a2d08f3a53:0x8e77c5a616050148!8m2!3d34.9110143!4d33.6376026&quot;&gt;
Maqam Al-Sultan Restaurant&lt;/a&gt; with great veg options, they served a delicious mesa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/mesa.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus didn’t offer great options for digital nomads in the middle of a pandemic. Meaning that most of the establishments weren’t prepared to meet rules like 1,5 meters distancing, etc. but I was lucky enough to find an amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Caff%C3%A8+Nero/@34.9110143,33.6288479,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x14e082dd1e710a25:0x665fdf3800d3f7ad!8m2!3d34.8896214!4d33.6371531&quot;&gt;Cafe Nero&lt;/a&gt; full of cats to make me company. This one is in Larnaka and it’s the best I could find, but I found out that most Cafe Neros are pretty great for a work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/cafe-nero.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent one afternoon in Nikosia. It’s a surprisingly poor city. You turn into a street and suddenly find yourself in front of the UN buffer zone that looks like a portal to a Mad Max world. I bet Nikosia is full of life and interesting experiences, but for me it was just a shock of poverty in the middle of the EU. It was the first time I saw kids begging for money in the streets in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/nikosia.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spent two days in an airbnb without wi-fi, that was challenging but also beautiful and contemplative experience. The guy who rented it had a huge collection of CDs and an old school sound system, which gave me a welcomed change of vibes from my usual hippie songs. I even wrote a bad poem in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/sad-bnb.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;2 dias em um airbnb triste&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eu olho pros meus vizinhos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;E eu os vejo atraves da varanda vazia e do vidro limpo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Da casa sem cortinas e luz brancas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Paredes nuas e corpos curvados&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cozinhando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sentados na mesa comendo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Conversando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Cozinhando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sentados na mesa comendo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Conversando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A varanda esteril&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sem luz sem plantas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;‘E um retrato feio, um portal pro passado de como eu me sentia a respeito de casas, rotinas e varandas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two weeks in the east I moved to the extreme opposite of the island. The west, in contrast with the east, is much more green and lushy. This was my second nest in the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/second_nest.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it came with a free beauty, stray(?), fluffyness that I named Biscoita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/biscoita.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found a beautiful restaurant nearby that was closed but left their wi-fi on, so I worked from there for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/sandwich-place.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visited some beautiful national parks like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Akamas+Peninsula+National+Park/@35.0429273,32.2293377,12z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x14e79fa9b5e044f7:0x83926ef7b0a13382!8m2!3d35.0429273!4d32.2993755&quot;&gt;Akamas Peninsula&lt;/a&gt; where I got some amazing views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I did the usual and followed the trail by foot to the Blue Lagoon, it was super worth it. When I did it there were many illegal hunters along the way. If you find them around there the number for the Cypriot police is 199 or 112.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/blue-lagoon.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close to this area I also went to the Aphrodite’s bath which is not very cool, I felt like walking into a tourist trap. However if you go up the mountain nearby, the Aphrodite’s Path, you’ll find some magical places :) It was one of my favorite random explorations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also visited the Paphos forest. There I just jumped out of the car in a sight seeing spot and went up a mountain nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/paphos-forest.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the west I explored some very cool Roman ruins, with the most well preserved mosaics I ever saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/paphos-ruins.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus has a beautiful ocean, some breath taking landscapes that go from desert, to pine tree forests, to something in between and is full of stray cats. Can’t say much about its people since my interactions with them in real life had a strict “useful end” that wasn’t related to befriending or anything like that but what I could perceive is, amazingly polite people that were ready to offer you a helping hand if you’re a clueless tourist. In my online interaction with locals most Cypriots shown to be extremely conservative folks, close minded for subjects like sex, nudity, politics and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this wasn’t what I expected! But it’s a first. I’ll try to be more specific about adventures in the next few posts. Currently I’m in my third week in Tenerife, which means, it’s been a while since I started this trip and didn’t write about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cyprus-aerial-view/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cyprus-aerial-view/</guid>
        
        
        <category>cyprus</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A note on corona</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My particular reason for travelling is trying to preserve my mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lived all my life in a very tropical part of Brazil and I just recently moved in to Berlin in 2019 meaning I had my first winter that year. It was tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 was very challenging for all of us and I had to fight many of my personal demons in this year. The prospect of spending a winter alone in the middle of a pandemic in Berlin was, honestly, terrifying to me so I decided to take the risk to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing it in the safest way possible. I respect all the enforced corona rules of the place I’m in + the rules I make myself because some places are just not strict enough according to my boundaries. You’ll notice I never talk about events, night life, parties or even other people in my posts and it’s not because I’m hiding it from anyone, it’s because I’m not partaking on any of this. I’m very in to all of these things but I’m giving my best to be safe and make others safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be not enough, travelling by plane is dangerous as fuck, I can see people around me openly disrespecting the rules, I’m afraid I’ll get sick and fuck myself or fuck others because I took their place in a hospital, I’m still very lonely and the world looks very scary. All of this is juggling in my head, but also the fact that I was spiralling down into deep depression for staying in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure if it was the right or better choice. I’m just trying to make the best of every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy this little diary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish you to stay healthy, strong and happy in this new year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-note-on-corona/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-note-on-corona/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
