<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wireless hippie</title>
    <description>an online diary for a wireless hippie</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:00:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A personal digression on sunsets: an illustrated book with Teneriffa's sunsets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was a teenager and lived in my Dorf in Brazil, I’d watch the sunset every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back then, I was living exclusively in the city for about 4 or 5 years. I don’t think I was entirely accostumated to the life in the city by the time and I was constantly referred as a “bicho do mato” by my family, which translates to “wild animal” - but in a cuter way… Anyway, I grew up in a farm, I spent most of my early childhood surrounded by nature and was in constant touch with it until I was 9 or 10. I think that shaped me into being a nature’s lover. This abrupt cut into a city life with no real access to nature got into me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The memories I had and this urge to go back to nature would sting me quite frequently, leaving a sour taste in my mouth for having moved to the cement jungle. I called myself an anarchoprimitivist and thought most technology was bad and that the human kind did wrong when moved itself away from God’s beautiful creations (I was some kind of religious kid back then). I’d hate on the city, the industry I’d see from my balcony, the car noises, the houses, the capitalists who were financing all of this - in summary I’d hate on a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there was this one thing that thrilled my imagination, made my heart beat faster and took a deep sigh out of my chest every time I past through it by the kitchen’s window: a huge forest surrounding an abandoned steel factory nearby. I think one day after rewatching the Lord of the Rings trilogy I finally took the courage to go there. So, I talked my best friend into it, and we waited for the right time in the class breaks to jump over the school’s wall “Into an adventure!”. The long story short is that we got robbed our sweet mp3 players by a crazy crack head with a knife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life. In a very dangerous country, I suppose. This was my first experience that put me in touch with the wickedness of the world. Before that I lived in a childhood’s utopia where everybody is nice to everybody else, after all, why would someone be evil? This question and the questions it implies and implicates really got into me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d spend hours writing endless rants about the meaning of life, physics and philosophy in my old school notebooks while contemplating sunset. Lots of the time these three things would merge together and I’d get myself wondering: what the fuck. I actually miss that a lot. I wanted to be a physicist for the longest time because of these exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/1sunset.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I went watching the sunset by myself in a nearby beach. Didn’t have any notebooks and no one recently robbed my mp3 player from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still, watching sunsets is an interesting exercise to me. It’s a moment where even though I have my phone and the whole world’s knowledge, and all of my friendships, and lots of my desires, expectations, fears, loves, inside this little black magic box, I don’t really feel the urge that consumes me while I have it with me at other more common times of the day to look at it. I sit there, and I look at the clouds and the beautiful colors the sun is throwing in there with the magic of optics and our atmosphere and I just feel gratitude for living in a world filled with beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/2sunset.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also an interesting exercise because all of the times I have gone there up until now, I’m the only female looking person that’s alone and I’m one of the few persons who are alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder why aren’t more females alone in the beach to watch the sunset? In Brazil my obvious answer would be: because it’s dangerous of course - but in Europe, I really wonder. Are women less lonely? They’re usually more often surrounded by friends and family? Do they suffer more pressure to be accompanied always? Are women more social beings on average? Or is there actually a degree of concern that their privacy or body or space won’t be respected because they’re females?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I like to be alone watching the sunset because it makes me feel alone. I don’t feel like I spend enough time with myself but being there makes me feel like I can finally breath and think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tenerife/3sunset.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch sunsets today but I don’t wonder anymore about the meaning of life, physics or philosophy. It’s funny to me, how it seems like I became a much more enclosed egocentric person looking so much at the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope it’s not a reflex of me becoming insensitive to the rest of the world’s problems because I moved into a place that doesn’t have such glaring problems like Brazil. I hope I’m doing this because my personal life is complicated now, more than it used to be. Maybe the answers I found for these elementary questions are now good enough to ease my soul, and now I feel more comfortable in focusing on improving myself and looking at the inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, I can’t wait to have the peace of mind and that itchy feeling of curiosity to spend sunsets thinking about the meaning of life, physics and philosophy again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/tenerife-sunset/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/tenerife-sunset/</guid>
        
        <category>Gran_Canary</category>
        
        
        <category>Travelling</category>
        
        <category>Personal</category>
        
        <category>Beach</category>
        
        <category>Mountain</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyprus aerial view</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For my first stop in this end of the world trip I chose Cyprus because of low incidence of corona + was supposed to meet with a friend there, but unfortunately didn’t work. Fortunately I still had another friend with me who accompanied my throughout Cyprus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus is a beautiful island in the mediterranean. In recent history it was occupied by Greeks, then by the Ottoman empire then by the British. It has a mix of all of these cultures and it’ll be difficult to find someone that doesn’t speak English in the Greek side. “Greek side” because the island is divided in half between the Greek and the Turkish with an UN buffer zone in the middle to avoid conflicts between both parts. But don’t worry, no imminent war starting, as long as the rest population is as chill about each other as the Cyprus subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus is the first desert-like place I’ve been to. I liked it at first, the desert landscapes awaken some interesting desolating feelings in my birdy soul, but I have to admit that after 2 weeks living in the desert, I was craving for some greenies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/desert.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first nest, near Larnaka. Had some great sunset views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/first-nest.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my stay in there I visited some nice places in the east. There are some beautiful beaches in the east coast with white sand and transparent mesmerizing blue waters. I recommend it strongly if you’re interested in beaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you’re around check the Capo Greco park. You can make some sight seeing in there + diving if it’s your thing. I unfortunately am still on a mission of improving my swimming skills. Since I almost died in the Aare River in Bern - Switzerland, I decided to be more respectful to water and more careful around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/capo.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus has a local pine tree, the Mastika, which produces a resine wich they use to make various products. It tastes like eating a tree somewhat, interesting flavor, recommend it.
They also have amazing flat bread with honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of food, I also went to this amazing restaurant in Larnaka, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Maqam+Al-Sultan+Restaurant/@34.9110143,33.6288479,15z/data=!4m8!1m2!2m1!1svegetarian+food+larnaka!3m4!1s0x14e082a2d08f3a53:0x8e77c5a616050148!8m2!3d34.9110143!4d33.6376026&quot;&gt;
Maqam Al-Sultan Restaurant&lt;/a&gt; with great veg options, they served a delicious mesa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/mesa.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus didn’t offer great options for digital nomads in the middle of a pandemic. Meaning that most of the establishments weren’t prepared to meet rules like 1,5 meters distancing, etc. but I was lucky enough to find an amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Caff%C3%A8+Nero/@34.9110143,33.6288479,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x14e082dd1e710a25:0x665fdf3800d3f7ad!8m2!3d34.8896214!4d33.6371531&quot;&gt;Cafe Nero&lt;/a&gt; full of cats to make me company. This one is in Larnaka and it’s the best I could find, but I found out that most Cafe Neros are pretty great for a work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/cafe-nero.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent one afternoon in Nikosia. It’s a surprisingly poor city. You turn into a street and suddenly find yourself in front of the UN buffer zone that looks like a portal to a Mad Max world. I bet Nikosia is full of life and interesting experiences, but for me it was just a shock of poverty in the middle of the EU. It was the first time I saw kids begging for money in the streets in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/nikosia.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spent two days in an airbnb without wi-fi, that was challenging but also beautiful and contemplative experience. The guy who rented it had a huge collection of CDs and an old school sound system, which gave me a welcomed change of vibes from my usual hippie songs. I even wrote a bad poem in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/sad-bnb.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;2 dias em um airbnb triste&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eu olho pros meus vizinhos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;E eu os vejo atraves da varanda vazia e do vidro limpo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Da casa sem cortinas e luz brancas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Paredes nuas e corpos curvados&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cozinhando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sentados na mesa comendo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Conversando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Cozinhando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sentados na mesa comendo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Conversando&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A varanda esteril&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sem luz sem plantas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;‘E um retrato feio, um portal pro passado de como eu me sentia a respeito de casas, rotinas e varandas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two weeks in the east I moved to the extreme opposite of the island. The west, in contrast with the east, is much more green and lushy. This was my second nest in the island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/second_nest.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it came with a free beauty, stray(?), fluffyness that I named Biscoita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/biscoita.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found a beautiful restaurant nearby that was closed but left their wi-fi on, so I worked from there for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/sandwich-place.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visited some beautiful national parks like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Akamas+Peninsula+National+Park/@35.0429273,32.2293377,12z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x14e79fa9b5e044f7:0x83926ef7b0a13382!8m2!3d35.0429273!4d32.2993755&quot;&gt;Akamas Peninsula&lt;/a&gt; where I got some amazing views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I did the usual and followed the trail by foot to the Blue Lagoon, it was super worth it. When I did it there were many illegal hunters along the way. If you find them around there the number for the Cypriot police is 199 or 112.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/blue-lagoon.JPEG&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close to this area I also went to the Aphrodite’s bath which is not very cool, I felt like walking into a tourist trap. However if you go up the mountain nearby, the Aphrodite’s Path, you’ll find some magical places :) It was one of my favorite random explorations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also visited the Paphos forest. There I just jumped out of the car in a sight seeing spot and went up a mountain nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/paphos-forest.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the west I explored some very cool Roman ruins, with the most well preserved mosaics I ever saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyprus/paphos-ruins.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyprus has a beautiful ocean, some breath taking landscapes that go from desert, to pine tree forests, to something in between and is full of stray cats. Can’t say much about its people since my interactions with them in real life had a strict “useful end” that wasn’t related to befriending or anything like that but what I could perceive is, amazingly polite people that were ready to offer you a helping hand if you’re a clueless tourist. In my online interaction with locals most Cypriots shown to be extremely conservative folks, close minded for subjects like sex, nudity, politics and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this wasn’t what I expected! But it’s a first. I’ll try to be more specific about adventures in the next few posts. Currently I’m in my third week in Tenerife, which means, it’s been a while since I started this trip and didn’t write about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/cyprus-aerial-view/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/cyprus-aerial-view/</guid>
        
        <category>Cyprus</category>
        
        <category>Mediterranean</category>
        
        <category>Greek</category>
        
        <category>Beach</category>
        
        <category>Mountain</category>
        
        <category>Forest</category>
        
        
        <category>Travelling</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        <category>Beach</category>
        
        <category>Mountain</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A note on corona</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My particular reason for travelling is trying to preserve my mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lived all my life in a very tropical part of Brazil and I just recently moved in to Berlin in 2019 meaning I had my first winter that year. It was tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 was very challenging for all of us and I had to fight many of my personal demons in this year. The prospect of spending a winter alone in the middle of a pandemic in Berlin was, honestly, terrifying to me so I decided to take the risk to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing it in the safest way possible. I respect all the enforced corona rules of the place I’m in + the rules I make myself because some places are just not strict enough according to my boundaries. You’ll notice I never talk about events, night life, parties or even other people in my posts and it’s not because I’m hiding it from anyone, it’s because I’m not partaking on any of this. I’m very in to all of these things but I’m giving my best to be safe and make others safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be not enough, travelling by plane is dangerous as fuck, I can see people around me openly disrespecting the rules, I’m afraid I’ll get sick and fuck myself or fuck others because I took their place in a hospital, I’m still very lonely and the world looks very scary. All of this is juggling in my head, but also the fact that I was spiralling down into deep depression for staying in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure if it was the right or better choice. I’m just trying to make the best of every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy this little diary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish you to stay healthy, strong and happy in this new year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/a-note-on-corona/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000https://wireless-hippie.github.io/a-note-on-corona/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
